<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Architecture on Coding notes - cheat sheets and snippets</title>
    <link>https://www.bustroker.com/tags/architecture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Architecture on Coding notes - cheat sheets and snippets</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.bustroker.com/tags/architecture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Architecture Principles for Developer Autonomy</title>
      <link>https://www.bustroker.com/notes/architecture-principles-for-developer-autonomy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.bustroker.com/notes/architecture-principles-for-developer-autonomy/</guid>
      <description>Goal Reduce architect gatekeeping by establishing clear principles that enable teams to make autonomous decisions. This requires two layers:&#xA;Architecture principles - high-level guidelines Concrete processes - specific governance artifacts (system documentation, context maps, component diagrams) Principle Management Treat principles as living artifacts Store principles in markdown within a version-controlled repository:&#xA;git init architecture-principles cd architecture-principles echo &amp;#34;# Architecture Principles&amp;#34; &amp;gt; principles.md git add principles.md git commit -m &amp;#34;Initial principles&amp;#34; Architects as collaborators, not gatekeepers Architecture teams should act as consultants and coaches, not approval boards.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solution Architecture Assessment Checklist</title>
      <link>https://www.bustroker.com/notes/solution-architecture-assessment-checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.bustroker.com/notes/solution-architecture-assessment-checklist/</guid>
      <description>Functional Assessment Identify business domains and their revenue impact:&#xA;Business Domains ├── Frontend functional areas ├── Regional/country-specific features └── Backoffice &amp;amp; BI/Reporting Document:&#xA;User requests the system cannot currently fulfill Manual tasks requiring automation Pain points from both end users and employees Non-Functional Assessment Current vs required vs critical thresholds:&#xA;Availability Reliability Performance Security Key metrics:&#xA;Concurrent users Request volume Identified bottlenecks Tech team pain points Modules and Components Modules (code organization):</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Architecture Interview Questions - Technical Reference</title>
      <link>https://www.bustroker.com/notes/architecture-interview-questions-technical-reference/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.bustroker.com/notes/architecture-interview-questions-technical-reference/</guid>
      <description>Architect vs Tech Lead Main concerns:&#xA;Architect: Cross-cutting concerns, system-wide design, technology strategy Tech Lead: Team execution, code quality, sprint delivery Key questions:&#xA;Most difficult aspect switching from TL to Solution Architect? Mentoring strategy? Establishing and enforcing guidelines/best practices? Relationship with Tech Leads in design/development? Web Architecture Styles Reference: Common Web Application Architectures&#xA;Monolithic&#xA;Single deployment unit Tight coupling N-layers&#xA;Presentation → Business Logic → Data Access Horizontal slicing Clean Architecture (Onion/Hexagonal)</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
