<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Architecture on Coding notes - and snippets</title>
    <link>https://www.bustroker.com/tags/architecture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Architecture on Coding notes - and snippets</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.bustroker.com/tags/architecture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Agentic AI Solutions Architecture .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.bustroker.com/notes/agentic-ai-solutions-architecture-.net/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.bustroker.com/notes/agentic-ai-solutions-architecture-.net/</guid>
      <description>This white paper is designed to align an extensive background in distributed systems with the specific requirements of an Agentic AI architecture role. It bridges the experience in .NET, Azure, and DDD with the cutting-edge patterns required for autonomous AI systems.&#xA;White Paper: Architecting Agentic AI Systems in .NET &amp;amp; Azure Prepared for: Senior Solutions Architect&#xA;Subject: Technical Foundations for Market-Leading Agentic AI in Pharma&#xA;1. Core Concepts: Beyond Simple LLMs While standard AI follows a linear path (Input → LLM → Output), Agentic AI introduces a &amp;ldquo;reasoning loop&amp;rdquo; where the system determines its own execution path.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agentic AI Solutions Architecture</title>
      <link>https://www.bustroker.com/notes/agentic-ai-solutions-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.bustroker.com/notes/agentic-ai-solutions-architecture/</guid>
      <description>White Paper: Core Knowledge for an Agentic AI Solutions Architect Focus areas: Prompt Engineering · Retrieval Pipelines · Evaluation Metrics Date: 27 Dec 2025 (Europe/Madrid)&#xA;Executive summary Agentic AI systems differ from “single-call” LLM apps: they plan, call tools, retrieve knowledge, iterate, and must be measurably reliable under real-world constraints (latency, cost, governance, safety). This white paper lays out practical fundamentals an Agentic AI Solutions Architect should know across:&#xA;Prompt engineering as policy + interface design between humans, tools, and models (not just “clever wording”).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Team growth support strategies</title>
      <link>https://www.bustroker.com/notes/team-growth-support-strategies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.bustroker.com/notes/team-growth-support-strategies/</guid>
      <description>1. How You Support Team Members’ Growth – Real Strategies 1️⃣ Create Technical Career Paths, Not Just Tasks You’ve led chapters, governance, and large teams. Use that.&#xA;What you do:&#xA;Define clear role expectations (e.g. Junior → Senior → Staff → Principal).&#xA;Make growth visible:&#xA;Junior → mastering delivery + testing. Senior → owning subsystems. Staff → architecture ownership, cross-team impact. In practice:&#xA;Run quarterly career conversations focused on:&#xA;“What kind of engineer do you want to be in 12 months?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Architecture Principles for Developer Autonomy</title>
      <link>https://www.bustroker.com/notes/architecture-principles-for-developer-autonomy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.bustroker.com/notes/architecture-principles-for-developer-autonomy/</guid>
      <description>Goal Reduce architect gatekeeping by establishing clear principles that enable teams to make autonomous decisions. This requires two layers:&#xA;Architecture principles - high-level guidelines Concrete processes - specific governance artifacts (system documentation, context maps, component diagrams) Principle Management Treat principles as living artifacts Store principles in markdown within a version-controlled repository:&#xA;git init architecture-principles cd architecture-principles echo &amp;#34;# Architecture Principles&amp;#34; &amp;gt; principles.md git add principles.md git commit -m &amp;#34;Initial principles&amp;#34; Architects as collaborators, not gatekeepers Architecture teams should act as consultants and coaches, not approval boards.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solution Architecture Assessment Checklist</title>
      <link>https://www.bustroker.com/notes/solution-architecture-assessment-checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.bustroker.com/notes/solution-architecture-assessment-checklist/</guid>
      <description>Functional Assessment Identify business domains and their revenue impact:&#xA;Business Domains ├── Frontend functional areas ├── Regional/country-specific features └── Backoffice &amp;amp; BI/Reporting Document:&#xA;User requests the system cannot currently fulfill Manual tasks requiring automation Pain points from both end users and employees Non-Functional Assessment Current vs required vs critical thresholds:&#xA;Availability Reliability Performance Security Key metrics:&#xA;Concurrent users Request volume Identified bottlenecks Tech team pain points Modules and Components Modules (code organization):</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Architecture Interview Questions - Technical Reference</title>
      <link>https://www.bustroker.com/notes/architecture-interview-questions-technical-reference/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.bustroker.com/notes/architecture-interview-questions-technical-reference/</guid>
      <description>Architect vs Tech Lead Main concerns:&#xA;Architect: Cross-cutting concerns, system-wide design, technology strategy Tech Lead: Team execution, code quality, sprint delivery Key questions:&#xA;Most difficult aspect switching from TL to Solution Architect? Mentoring strategy? Establishing and enforcing guidelines/best practices? Relationship with Tech Leads in design/development? Web Architecture Styles Reference: Common Web Application Architectures&#xA;Monolithic&#xA;Single deployment unit Tight coupling N-layers&#xA;Presentation → Business Logic → Data Access Horizontal slicing Clean Architecture (Onion/Hexagonal)</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
